Howard Wise Gallery
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Howard Wise Gallery records
1943-1969
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Howard Wise Gallery
8.4 linear feet
The records of the Howard Wise Gallery in New York, and its predecessor the Howard Wise Gallery of Present Day Painting and Sculpture in Cleveland, Ohio, measure 8.4 linear feet and date from 1943-1969. Records consist of correspondence, artist files, exhibition files, business records, and miscellaneous records that document the activities of Wise's gallery in Cleveland from 1957-1961 and, to a much lesser extent, his gallery in New York City from 1960-1968. Wise's influential work with video artists is not documented in the collection as it occurred after the period covered by the records donated to the Archives.
Historical Note
After twenty-five years as president of Arco Company, his family's industrial paint and varnish manufacturing business in Cleveland, Howard Wise (1903-1989) sold his interest in the business and began to pursue his own artistic interests. The Howard Wise Gallery of Present Day Painting and Sculpture opened in Cleveland in 1957 and operated for the next five years. It first showed School of Paris and New York painters and also sold prints. With the exception of a few collectors and loyal customers, Clevelanders did not appreciate Wise's efforts to bring the best new art from all over the world to the city. The Cleveland Plain Dealer ran several editorials ridiculing modern art in general and Howard Wise and his gallery in particular. Attendance was poor and Wise decided to relocate to New York.
After a year of searching for a suitable location and renovating the space, Howard Wise Gallery opened at 50 West 57th Street in 1960. The gallery generated excitement among visitors and artists, and sales and attendance were much better than in Cleveland. After closing the Cleveland gallery in 1961 Wise never again returned to his native city. Despite being well received and conducting significantly more business in New York, the gallery was not a great financial success. Between 1962 and 1965, art consultant Douglas MacAgy, a friend and the former director of the Dallas Museum of Art, worked with Wise in running the gallery. Although the critics were not always favorably impressed, Howard Wise Gallery had a significant following and made important contributions through its support of the use of technology in art, specifically kinetic and light sculpture and the video art movement.
By the late 1960s, Wise recognized that a gallery setting was not suitable for many of the new art forms. He closed Howard Wise Gallery in 1970 so that he could focus his energy and resources on exploring the best way to support environmental sculpture, political work, and video art. Wise founded Electronic Arts Intermix in 1971. Originally an artist-run umbrella organization, today Electronic Arts Intermix is a non-profit videotape distribution service and editing facility, that has amassed a very important and highly regarded video art collection.
Scope and Content Note
The records of the Howard Wise Gallery in New York, and its predecessor the Howard Wise Gallery of Present Day Painting and Sculpture in Cleveland, Ohio, measure 8.4 linear feet and date from 1943-1969. Records consist of correspondence, artist files, exhibition files, business records, and miscellaneous records that document the activities of Wise's gallery in Cleveland from 1957-1961 and, to a much lesser extent, his gallery in New York City from 1960-1968. While gallery owner Howard Wise was noted for his interest in technology in art, and presented some of the earliest and most influential exhibitions of kinetic and light sculpture and video art, the gallery's important and influential work with video artists occurred after the period covered by the records donated to the Archives.
Correspondence (2 linear feet) documents the operations of Wise's galleries in Cleveland and New York. A few subject files and a small amount of Howard Wise's personal correspondence (some predating the gallery) are also included in this series.
Artist files (3.25 linear feet) contain varying combinations of correspondence, printed material, notes and writings, and photographs. Most artists represented in this series were affiliated with Howard Wise Gallery either in Cleveland or New York City, but some files are for individuals of potential interest to the gallery. A small series of exhibition files (0.75 feet) containing correspondence, printed material, guest lists, and notes is far from complete. The files primarily document shows presented at Howard Wise Gallery of Present Day Painting and Sculpture in Cleveland, although a few are for exhibitions held in New York.
Business records (2.4 linear feet) include records of cash disbursements that are primarily for Howard Wise's travel and entertainment expenses. Business memoranda and correspondence between the Cleveland and New York galleries document sales, inventory, shipments and financial information. Miscellaneous records (3 folders) consist of writings by Howard Wise and Douglas MacAgy, and photographs of the Howard Wise Gallery of Present Day Painting and Sculpture in Cleveland.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 5 series:
Series 1: Correspondence, 1943-1967 (Boxes 1-2; 2.0 linear ft.)
Series 2: Artist Files, 1950-1968 (Boxes 3-6; 3.25 linear ft.)
Series 3: Exhibition Files, 1957-1968 (Boxes 6-7; 0.75 linear ft.)
Series 4: Business Records, 1957-1969 (Boxes 7-9; 2.4 linear ft.)
Series 5: Miscellaneous Records, 1957-circa 1960 (Box 9; 3 folders)
Index Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following index terms. People, families and organizations are listed under "Subjects" when they are the topic of collection contents and under "Names" when they are creators or contributors.
Subjects-Topical:
Art galleries, Commercial -- New York (State) -- New York; Art galleries, Commercial -- Ohio -- Cleveland; Art, Modern; Kinetic sculpture; Video art
Types of Materials:
Photographs
Names:
Wise, Howard; MacAgy, Douglas, 1913-
Provenance
The Howard Wise Gallery records were donated to the Archives of American Art in 1971 by Howard Wise.
Separated Material
Materials consisting of publicity, correspondence, exhibition plans, text of an exhibition catalog, and photographs relating to Howard Kiesler were loaned to the Archives for microfilming in 1970. The records were subsequently returned to the Howard Wise Gallery and are available on reels N70-77 but are not described in this finding aid.
Related Material
Also found in the Archives of American Art is an oral history interview with Howard Wise conducted by Paul Cummings on February 22, 1971. The Harvard Art Museum Archives also holds archival records of the Howard Wise Gallery.
Restrictions on Access
The collection is open for research. Use requires an appointment.
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Correspondence, 1943-1967, Series 1:; (Boxes 1-2; 2.0 linear ft.)
  Correspondence with collectors, clients, art dealers, museums, arts organizations, and suppliers of goods and services documents the Howard Wise Gallery of Present Day Painting and Sculpture, Cleveland, Ohio, and the Howard Wise Gallery, New York, New York. A few subject files and a small amount of Howard Wise's personal correspondence (some predating the gallery) are interfiled with the alphabetical correspondence in 1.1: Correspondence, A-Z.
  This series is arranged as 2 subseries in alphabetical and chronological order respectively.
  1.1: Correspondence, A-Z, 1943-1967
  1.2: New York Gallery Correspondence, 1962-1965
  - Correspondence, A-Z, 1943-1967, 1.1:
    - Abrams, H. N., Incorporated - American District Telegraph Co., 1958-1965 (Box 1)
      Abrams, H. N., Incorporated
      Abrams, Morris
      Academy of Medicine of Cleveland
      Adath Jeshurun
      Addison Gallery of American Art
      Addressograph-Multigraph Corporation
      Adler, Arthur M., Jr.
      Agris Verlag Krefeld und Baden-Baden
      Akron Beacon-Journal
      Alan Stone Gallery (see: Stone Gallery, Alan)
      Albert R. Lee and Co., Inc. (see: Lee, and Co., Inc., Albert R.)
      Alevy and Cantor
      Alexander Iolas Gallery (see: Iolas Gallery, Alexander)
      Allen Inc., Publishers, Howard
      Alpers, Dr. N.
      Amel Gallery
      American Academy in Rome
      American District Telegraph Co.
    - American Federation of Arts, 1956-1966, (2 folders) (Box 1)
    - American Honda - Art Colony, 1957-1965 (Box 1)
      American Honda
      American Iron and Steel Institute
      American Mutual Liability Insurance Company
      American Republic Insurance Company
      A. M. Sachs Gallery (see: Sachs Gallery, A. M.)
      Anderson Gallery, David
      Andrews Moving and Storage Co.
      Angle, Gertrude N.
      Ansbacher, Carolyn
      Architects Collaborative
      Architectural Forum
      Arco Company
      Art Colony
    - Art Dealers Association, Inc., 1961-1965, (2 folders) (Box 1)
    - Art Gallery of Toronto - Ayers, Kirby, 1957-1964 (Box 1)
      Art Gallery of Toronto
      Arthur Tooth and Sons, Ltd. (see: Tooth and Sons, Ltd., Arthur)
      Art Information Service (see also: Chamberlain, Betty)
      Art Institute of Zanesville, Ohio
      Artist Tenants Association
      Artistes de France Associates Incorporated
      Artists Equity Association
      Arts Club of Chicago
      Art:USA:NOW
      Ashbrook, J. B.
      Aujourd'hui
      Austin, Allan
      A. W. Fenton Co., Inc. (see: Fenton Co., Inc., A. W.)
      Ayer and Son, Inc., A. W.
      Ayers, Kirby
    - Babcock Gallery - B'nai Brith Hillel Foundation of Western Reserve University, 1957-1965 (Box 1)
      Babcock Gallery
      Baekland, Brooks
      Baker, Oliver and Sylvia
      Baker, Richard Brown
      Balaban, M.
      Balkwill, S. Ward
      Ball State Teachers College
      Barker, Walter
      Barnard College Club of Cleveland
      Barnes, Marion J.
      Barone Gallery
      Barton, Bruce, Jr.
      Bates, Mary Louise
      Baum School of the Allentown Art Museum
      Baycrafters
      Bayer, Eleanor
      Baylor University
      Beaird, Jane R.
      Bedi-Rassy Art Foundry
      Bell, J.
      Beneson, Charles B.
      Bennett, Richard M.
      Berger, Frank
      Bergmann, Robert
      Bertha Schaefer Gallery (see: Schaefer Gallery, Bertha)
      Bescherner, H.
      Bey, Edie
      Bianchini Gallery
      Biddle, Mary A.
      Biehle, Helen C.
      Bill, Max
      Bing, Louis S.
      Birmingham Festival of Arts
      Bishop, Robert H.
      Blesh, Rudi
      B. L. Marble Chair Company (see: Marble Chair Company, B. L.)
      B'nai Brith Hillel Foundation of Western Reserve University
    - Bode, Arnold - Butler Institute of American Art, 1956-1965 (Box 1)
      Bode, Arnold
      Bolles Gallery
      Bollinger Transport
      Bolton, Frances P.
      Bolton, Kenyon C.
      Bond, Douglas
      Bonfoey Company
      Boone, Pat
      Borgenicht Gallery, Inc., Grace
      Borsick, Helen
      Bosse, M. J.
      Boston Truck Company
      Bourlet and Sons, Ltd., James
      Boutourllilne, Serge
      Bovasso, Julie
      Bowker Company, R. R.
      Bragazzi, Olive
      Brahan, Diane W.
      Brantford Arts Council
      Brata Frame Shop
      Brazilian Consulate General
      Breeze, Marion
      Brighten, Jonny
      Broadway Maintenance Corp.
      Broder, Harry
      Bronfman, Anne
      Brooklyn Heights Art Show and Sale and Auction (see: Charity Exhibitions)
      Brooklyn Museum
      Brooks, David
      Brophy, William E.
      Brown, Leonard
      Brown University
      Brownheim, Mary and L. M.
      Bruce, Alice
      Buchanan, Harvey
      Buckwalter, Charles
      Budworth and Son, Inc., W. S.
      Bulger, E.
      Bundy Art Gallery (see: Carpenter, Harlow)
      Burden, William A. M.
      Burkhardt, Rudy
      Burnham, J. S.
      Bury, Pol
      Butler Institute of American Art
    - Cage, John - Carmel Gallery, Hilda, 1957-1962 (Box 1)
      Cage, John
      Cain, Edward R.
      Calray Sales and Service Inc.
      Cambridge Camera Exchange
      Camp Wildwood (see also: Wildwood, Camp)
      Canton Art Institute
      Cardona, Rudi and Electra
      Carmel Gallery, Hilda
    - Carpenter, Harlow (Bundy Art Gallery), 1961-1965 (Box 1)
    - Casa la Rosa - Chamberlain, Betty, 1956-1965 (Box 1)
      Casa la Rosa
      Catholic Student Center of Minnesota
      Cauduro, Ed
      CBS News
      Chakin, Nathan
      Chamberlain, Betty (see also: Art Information Service)
    - Charity Exhibitions, 1960-1963 (Box 1)
    - Chase Manhattan Bank - Cleveland Institute of Art, 1952-1964 (Box 1)
      Chase Manhattan Bank
      Chemists' Club
      Ching, William
      Chrysler, Walter P., Jr.
      Cimaise
      Cinema 16
      Citron, Kasper H.
      City Art Museum of St. Louis
      City of New York
      Clague, John
      Clare College
      Clark, Harold T.
      Clayburgh, A. M.
      Clert, Iris
      Cleveland Clinic Foundation
      Cleveland Convention and Visitors Bureau, Inc.
      Cleveland Council on World Affairs
      Cleveland Institute of Art
    - Cleveland Museum of Art, 1943-1964, (2 folders) (Box 1)
    - Cleveland Museum of Natural History - Cummings, Willard, 1954-1964 (Box 1)
      Cleveland Museum of Natural History
      Cleveland News
      Cleveland Paint Varnish and Lacquer Association
      Cleveland Press
      Coe, Ralph M.
      Cohen, Barbara Joseloff
      Cohen, Bess J.
      Cohen, Ira
      Cohen, John H.
      Cohen, Joseph H.
      Cole, Timothy
      Collegiate School
      Colorado Springs Fine Arts Center
      Columbia Museum of Art
      Comité des arts du congrés pur la liberté de la culture
      Conde, John P.
      Container Corporation of America
      Contemporaries Gallery
      Contemporary Furniture Showrooms, Inc.
      Continental Bank
      Cook, Mrs. John
      Cooper, Mr.
      Cooper, Mrs. Henry C.
      Corcoran, Arthur
      Cordier and Ekstrom, Inc.
      CORE
      Cornell University
      Corporate Publications, Inc.
      Corrigan, Robert
      Council for the Retarded Child
      Cowan, Robert D.
      Cowie Galleries
      Cowles, John, Jr.
      Cramer, Red and Beth
      Cramer, Worth C.
      Cranbrook Academy of Art
      Credit Bureau of Greater New York, Inc.
      Crehan, Hubert
      Crespi, H.
      Cross, Christopher
      Crown Publishers, Inc.
      Cummings, Willard
    - Danes, Gibson A. - Dorfman, Ralph, 1957-1964 (Box 1)
      Danes, Gibson A.
      D'Arcy Advertising Agency
      D'Arcy Galleries
      Davenport, Leroy
      David Anderson Gallery (see: Anderson Gallery, David)
      Davidson, Barbara
      Davis, Abram D.
      Day, Lucien
      Day Nursery Association of Cleveland
      deAenllie Gallery, Roland
      Deitsch, Peter H.
      Delgado Museum of Fine Arts
      Dempsey, Jeanette
      Denny, Joann
      De Sauzé, Emile B.
      Des Moines Art Center
      Design Research
      Detroit Institute of Arts
      Dewey, Joseph
      Diamond, Harold
      Dickens,Charles
      Dietz, David
      Dilexi Gallery
      Dill, Bayard
      Dorfman, Ralph
    - Dotrement, Philippe, 1963-1964 (Box 1)
    - Douglass College - Feigen, Richard L., 1957-1963 (Box 1)
      Douglass College
      Dowling, Robert W.
      Downey, Morton
      Downtown Gallery
      Duncan, Alexander D.
      Duschnes, Philip G.
      Dykes, Victor
      Eason, Winston
      Eden, Paul L.
      Editions de la Connaissance
      ?ditions M. Lacouriere
      Edmunds Scientific Co.
      Educational Alliance
      Efron, George
      Eiseman, Helen
      Eliot, Elizabeth
      Elliott, Stanley B.
      Emerman, Bernard
      Emerson Public Schools
      England, Dan
      Ernest Wittenberg Public Relations (see: Wittenberg, Ernest, Public Relations)
      ESSO Research and Engineering Company
      Esther Robles Gallery (see: Robles Gallery, Esther)
      Evansville Museum of Arts and Science
      Eyles, Sybil
      Facchetti, Paul
      Fahnestock, Samuel L.
      Fairleigh Dickinson University
      Fairweather-Hardin Gallery
      FAR Gallery
      Feigen, Richard L.
    - Fenton Co., Inc., A. W.1957-1964 (Box 1)
    - Ferus Gallery - Garfinkel, Stanley,1957-1964 (Box 1)
      Ferus Gallery
      Fike, C. A.
      Finch College Museum
      Fine Arts Associates
      Fine, Jacob
      FIT Alumni Association (see: Charity Exhibitions)
      Fitch, George H.
      Flannigan, Dennis
      Flesheim, S. W.
      Flint Institute of Arts
      Foshee, Rufus
      Four Seasons
      Fox, Claire
      Freeman, Stanley
      French, Winsor
      Fried Gallery, Rose
      Friedman, Frances R.
      Frumkin, Allen
      Fuldheim, Dorothy
      Gabriel, Robert
      Galerie Arnaud
      Galerie Claude Bernard
      Galerie d'Art Moderne
      Galerie D. Benador
      Galerie de France
      Galerie im Griechenbeisl
      Galerie Springer Berlin
      Galerie Stadler
      Galleria Nazionale d'Arte Moderna
      Gallery Conquistador
      Gallery Moos
      Gallery One
      Gallery Passport, Ltd.
      Gandola, Paul
      Gans, David M.
      Garfinkel, Stanley
    - Gauguin (carved cabinet), 1964 (Box 1)
    - Geigy Chemical Corporation - Gimpel Fils, Ltd., 1957-1964 (Box 1)
      Geigy Chemical Corporation
      Geller, Abraham W.
      General Fireproofing Company
      Gerlach, Rose D.
      Gerson, Otto, Gallery
      Gibbs, David
      Gifford, Sanford
      Gilford Leather Co.
      Gimpel Fils, Ltd.
    - Gingrich, Arnold - Gutman, Walter, 1957-1965 (Box 1)
      Gingrich, Arnold
      Glickman, Charles
      Goeritz, Mathias
      Golodowsky, Noah
      Gonzales, Boyer
      Goodman, N. N.
      Goodman, Percival
      Goodman, Robert B.
      Goodrich Industrial Products
      Goodsell, C. H.
      Gotham Gallery
      Grace Borgenicht Gallery, Inc. (see: Borgenicht Gallery, Inc., Grace)
      Graff, Robert D.
      Graham Gallery
      Green, Mrs. Charles (Peggy)
      Green, Edward J.
      Greenstein, A. M.
      Gres Gallery
      Gries, Robert Hays
      Gropius, Walter
      Grossman, Ethel
      Grossman, Marc J.
      Grove Press
      Grund, David
      Gruzen, B. Sumner
      Guggenheim Foundation
      Guillermin and Mollet
      Gump's
      Gutman, Walter
    - Haas, Albert - Hurd, K. F., 1950-1966 (Box 1)
      Haas, Albert
      Hagen, Yvonne
      Hahn Bros. Fireproof Warehouses, Inc.
      Hall, John H.
      Halle Brothers
      Halle, Hortense
      Halle, Kay
      Halley, Donald M.
      Hallmark Art Awards
      Hammarstrum, Marianne
      Hamon, Jake L. and Nancy B.
      Hancy, Lawrence
      Hannibal, J.
      Harper's Bazaar
      Harris, Alfred W,
      Harrison and Abramowit
      Haskins, Lester
      Hathaway Brown School
      Haupt, Ira
      Hawken School
      Hawkins, Erick
      Hazen, Joseph H.
      Hecht, Sidney A.
      Heller, Ben
      Hempel, Gardiner
      Henderson, Priscilla A. B.
      Herbert, David
      Herron Art Institute, John
      Hilda Carmel Gallery (see: Carmel Gallery, Hilda)
      Hillman, Kay Merrill
      Hiser, Mrs. Harold R., Jr.
      H. N. Abrams, Incorporated (see: Abrams Incorporated, H. N.)
      Hoffman, Junius
      Hollis, H. C.
      Holzheimers' Interiors
      Hooker, Mrs. R. W.
      Hoover Company
      Horan, Frank J.
      Horung, Robert
      Horton, John
      House and Garden
      Howard, Alice
      Hrabick, William J.
      Hurd, K. F.
    - IBM Proposal - Joslyn Art Museum, 1957-1965 (Box 1)
      IBM Proposal
      Igell, Herman
      Illinois Wesleyan University
      Institute of Contemporary Arts, London
      International Directory of Arts
      Iolas Gallery, Alexander
      Irwin, Spencer D.
      Isaacs Gallery
      Isaacs, Reginald R.
      Isserman, Ferdinand M.
      It Is
      Jackson Gallery, Martha
      James Bourlet and Sons, Ltd. (see: Bourlet and Sons, Ltd., James)
      James Gallery
      James, Wanda
      Janis, Sidney, Gallery
      Janss, Edwin
      Jayfro
      Jerrold Morris International Gallery Limited (see: Morris International Gallery Limited, Jerrold)
      John and Mabel Ringling Museum of Art (see: Ringling Museum of Art, John and Mabel)
      John Herron Art Institute (see: Herron Art Institute, John)
      Johns-Manvillle
      Johnson, Margarita
      Johnson, Philip C.
      Johnson, Theodate
      Joseph, Frank E.
      Joslyn Art Museum
    - Kane, Michael - KYW Television, 1957-1964 (Box 1)
      Kane, Michael
      Kareka, R. C.
      Katan, Maurits
      Kelleher, Joe
      Kelsey, Sam
      Kennedy, Jacqueline
      Kenneth Lynch and Sons (see: Lynch and Sons, Kenneth)
      Kent School
      Ketterer, Roman Norbert
      Kiefer, Anna A.
      Kinney, Anna
      Kirstein, Lincoln
      KLH Research
      Knox, Seymour H.
      Kootz, Samuel
      Kornbluh, Edward C.
      Krakower, Arnold
      Kramer, Hilton
      Krannert Art Museum (see: University of Illinois)
      Kronick, William
      Krotinger, Myron N.
      Kryl, Bohumir
      Kulicke Frames, Inc.
      Kunstsammlung Nordhein-Westfalen
      KYW Radio
      KYW Television
    - La Hume Galerie, 1957-1963 (Box 1)
    - Lakewood Art League - Lerner Publications, 1952-1964 (Box 1)
      Lakewood Art League
      Lambert, J. O.
      Landor, Walter and Associates
      Lang, Fran and H. Jack
      Lannan Foundation
      Lannan, J. Patrick
      Lansing, Charles B.
      Laurel School
      Laurence, Dean
      Lazar, Albert
      Lebron, James J.
      Lee and Co., Inc., Albert R.
      Lefebre Gallery
      Legros, M. J.
      Leighton, Kaye
      Lemmon, Cyril W.
      Lerner Publications
    - Lescaze, William - Madison, Geraldine, 1958-1964 (Box 2)
      Lescaze, William
      Levin, Jeanne
      Lewis, C. McKenzie
      Lidgerwood, William V.
      Life Magazine
      Lipinsky, Lino S.
      List, Mrs. Albert
      Litchfield, Dorothy Hale
      Little Red School House (see: Charity Exhibitions)
      Littlefield, William H.
      Living Theatre
      Lloyd, Mrs. H. Gates
      Loesser, Mrs. Arthur
      l'Oeuvre Gravée
      Long Beach Island Art Foundation
      Lord, John
      Love, Ruth Winfield
      Lucas, John and Sikie
      Lye, Ann
      Lynch, Kenneth and Sons
      MacDowell Colony
      Macomber, Connie and Pete
      Madison, Geraldine
    - Maeght, Aimé (Galerie Maeght; Maeght Editeur), 1957-1959 (Box 2)
    - Magriel, Paul - Minerva Printing Corp., 1951-1965 (Box 2)
      Magriel, Paul
      Majewski, Marek
      Mandel, Samuel
      Mannes, L.
      Marble Chair Company, B. L.
      Maremont, Arnold H.
      Maringer, Carol
      Marsh and McLennan
      Marshall, Marvin V.
      Martha Jackson Gallery (see: Jackson Gallery, Martha)
      Martin Widdifield Gallery (see: Widdifield Gallery, Martin)
      Marx, Hilda
      Massie, Edward
      Massilon Museum
      Mattos, Astres
      Mayer Gallery
      Mayo Hill Colony Club
      Mayse, Purney
      McBride, Mrs. Malcolm L.
      McClellan, H. Chad
      McDonald, Dorcas
      McGee, Winston
      McGinnis, Mrs. Patrick
      McLaughlin, Charles E.
      Mead Corporation
      Mechanical Engineering
      Medusa, La
      Melamed, A.
      Mellon, Gertrude A.
      Merrill, Turben and Company, Inc.
      Metro
      Metropolitan Museum of Art
      Meyer, Carl
      Meyer, Carl F. G., IV
      Mezzalama, Francesco
      Midwestern University
      Minerva Printing Corp.
    - Minneapolis Institute of Arts - Museum of Fine Arts, Houston, 1956-1964 (Box 2)
      Minneapolis Institute of Arts
      Minnesota Mining and Manufacturing Co.
      Modernage Photographic Services
      Moderna Museet
      Molnar, Eleanor
      Molton Gallery
      Montefiore Home
      Moore, Dan T.
      Moore, George S.
      Moore, Mrs, Paul
      Moreland, C. A.